我们已经谈了很多关于图像如何在MATLAB中表示为矩阵的讨论。
We have talked quite a bit about how an image is represented as a matrix inside a MATLAB.
相反，我们使用MATLAB工具创建的矩阵可以显示为图像。
Conversely, a matrix that we create using MATLAB tools can be displayed as an image.
所以我们现在要做的是使用一些MATLAB的基本图像创建工具
So what we are going to do now is use some of MATLAB’s fundamental image creation tools
产生一些测试图像。所以我们将纯粹通过代码创建一个新的图像。
to produce some test images. So we are going to create a new image purely through code.
因此，让我们首先分配一个工作空间变量im，即我的图像标准名称。
So let’s start off by assigning to a workspace variable im, my standard name for an image.
我将使用函数零。它的作用是创建一个具有维度的矩阵
I am going to use the function zeros. And what that does is create a matrix with dimensions
200乘200，该矩阵中的所有元素都是零。我要设置一个元素
200 by 200 and all the elements in that matrix are zeroes. And I am going to set one element
它的值为1.现在我可以显示我刚创建的图像矩阵
of that to the value of 1. Now I can display this matrix that I just created as an image
我们可以看到的是这很大程度上是黑色的，因为所有的像素都是零，这代表了
and what we can see is this largely black, because all the pixels are zero, which represents
在最左上角的黑色和上方，你可以看到一小块白色。那
black and up in the top left-most corner you can see a tiny little patch of white. That
是我设置的值为1-1的一个像素，表示白色。
is the one pixel that I set to the value of 1—1 representing white.
现在，我可以在这里创建一个稍大的对象，我将要做的是内部
Now, I can create a slightly bigger object in this and what I am going to do is, within
这个矩阵，我将设置从第150行到第160行的所有像素，以及所有列
this matrix, I am going to set all the pixels from row 150 to row 160, and all the columns
从第60列到第70列，我将把它们设置为0.5。就是这样
from column 60 to column 70, and I am going to set those to a value of 0.5. So that is
黑色和白色之间的灰色。我将设置所有这些元素
a grey, half way between black and white. And I am going to set all those elements of
矩阵的值为0.5，现在我可以再次显示该矩阵，我们看到了
the matrix to the value of 0.5, now I can display that matrix again and we see we have
在图像中创建了一个小灰色方块。所以我们只是通过写作来创建一个图像
created a small grey square in the image. So we are creating an image simply by writing
码。工具箱包含要创建的功能
code. The toolbox contains a function to create
界。我打算这样做，我打算调用circle函数，它被调用
circles. I am going to do that, I am going to call the circle function, it is called
kcircle。而且我要说我想要一个半径为30的圆-我们看到它已经创建了
kcircle. And I am going to say I want a circle of radius 30—we see that it has created
尺寸为61乘61的矩阵。让我们来看看我们刚刚创建的这个东西。
a matrix of dimensions 61 by 61. Let’s have a look at this thing that we just created.
我们在这里可以看到该矩阵的图像表示。我们可以使用idisp来探索它，
We can see here is the image representation of that matrix. We can explore it using idisp,
我们看到这里的所有像素，这些矩阵元素的值都是
and we see that all these pixels in here, these matrix elements, have got a value of
所有这些不在圆圈中的值都是0。
1. And all these ones which don’t lie in the circle have got a value of 0.
所以这个函数返回了一个方形的矩阵，其中的元素也是
So this function has returned a matrix which is square and the elements in that are either
如果它们不属于圆圈，则为0;如果它们属于圆圈，则为白色。
0 if they don’t belong inside the circle and white if they do belong inside the circle.
现在我们现在可以做的是将这个圆圈粘贴到我们之前的图像中，
Now what we can do now is actually paste this circle into the image that we had before,
所以，让我们回到刚才的形象。
so let’s just go back to the image that we had a moment ago.
我要将圆圈粘贴到该图像中，我这样做。我要去
And I am going to paste the circle into that image and I do it like this. I am going to
制作圆圈，而不是明亮的白色，我会使它变得稍微亮一点灰色
make the circle, not bright white, I am going to make it a slightly brighter grey then the
广场是。所以我将乘以圆圈中的所有元素
square was. So I am going to multiply all of the elements in the circle by the value
为0.7，因此它将具有70％的灰度值。而我将用它来圈出圆圈
of 0.7, so it will have a 70% grey value. And I am going to place the circle with its
因此，这是100和100的u坐标
centre at 100 by 30. So that is the u coordinate of a 100 and the
v坐标30.我现在所做的就是更新元素
v coordinate of 30. All I have done now is updated the elements
在矩阵中。我之前拥有的价值，现在它已经粘贴了一个圆圈。
in the matrix im. The value that I had before and now it has got a circle pasted into it.
那么让我们来看看。
So let’s have a look at that.
我们看到图像现在包含一个正方形和一个圆圈。Toolbox还有其他一些功能
And we see that the image now contains a square and a circle. Toolbox has got some other functions
用于在矩阵内创建图形实体。另一个功能是iline，并绘制了一个
for creating graphical entities within a matrix. Another function is iline and that draws a
行成矩阵。所以我要在matixim中划一条线。
line into a matrix. So I am going to draw a line into the matix im.
该线将从坐标30开始40，并且它将在190到190之间，
The line is going to start at coordinate 30 by 40. And it is going to go to 150 by 190,
我将使它的值为90％灰色。
and I’m going to make it have a value of 90% grey.
让我们看一下。我们有一个矩阵，现在包含一个正方形，一条线，
Let’s display that. And there we have a matrix which now contains a square, a line,
一个圆圈和一个明亮的像素。Toolbox有一些功能可以轻微创建
a circle and a single bright pixel. Toolbox has got some functions to create slightly
更精细的测试模式，通过测试模式功能访问。在这里，我要去
more elaborate test patterns, accessed through the test pattern function. And here I am going
创建一个斜坡函数，我将创建一个尺寸为200乘200像素的图像。
to create a ramp function and I am going to create an image of dimensions 200 by 200 pixels.
让我们来看看。在这里，我们有一个所谓的灰度
And let’s have a look at that. And here we have what is called a grey scale
坡道。我们来看看这里的灰度值。它们相当低
ramp. Let’s have a look at the grey scale values in here. They are quite low, about
0.5，当我们水平移动时，它会变得更亮更明亮
0.5 and as we move horizontally it gets brighter and brighter all the way up
因此，如果它是灰度斜坡模式，我们可以创建更精细的测试模式
to 1. So if it is a grey scale ramp pattern we can create more elaborate test patterns
例如正方形或圆形网格。这是一个例子。我们将它分配给输出
such as grid of squares or circles. Here is an example. We assign it to an output
变量im，使用测试模式函数。要求正方形。我们想要输出图像
variable im, use the test pattern function. Ask for squares. We want the output image
为200像素乘200像素。我们希望正方形的间距为50像素
to be 200 pixels by 200 pixels. We want the squares to be on a 50 pixel spacing and we
希望方块是25像素的正方形。让我们显示那个图像。我们有一个16格的网格。
want the squares to be 25 pixels square. Let’s display that image. And there we have a grid of 16 squares.